■
双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译    北落师门
翻译    唐朝栗子
翻译    守誓剑
君临 King's Landing
红堡 Red Keep
翻译   龙的命根子
龙石岛 Dragonstone
校对   北落师门
校对   旧镇老翁
审查   Barossa
审查   临冬城的狮子
铁群岛  派克城
Ironislands Pyke
精校  龙的命根子
时间轴   加文·维斯特林
临冬城 Winterfell
后期   加文·维斯特林
策划   baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
维斯·多斯拉克Vaes Dothrak
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
权力的游戏
第二季 第三集
衣柜字幕组
第三集  “逝者不死”
"What is Dead May Never Die"
滚蛋 你们都滚蛋
Out, all of you.
这杂种摸进了他不该去的地方！
Bastard's been meddling where he shouldn't!
我要你和你的崽子
I want you and your men
卡斯特
野人
杰奥·莫尔蒙
“熊老” 守夜人总司令
滚蛋
gone.
叫他们乖乖照办
And you will make this right.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
出去等着
Wait outside.
- 总司令大人  - 出去！
- Lord Commander.  - Now!
- 总司令大人  - 退下
- Lord Commander.  - Leave us.
你都干了什么？
What did you do?
我跟踪了他
I followed him.
他把婴儿抱进树林 都是新生儿
He took the baby into the woods, the newborn.
那关你什么事？
What business is that of yours?
不 你不明白
No, you don't understand.
他杀了他们 杀了所有的男孩
He's killing them, all the boys.
你早就知道
You know.
野人侍奉的神祗比起你我的神要残暴得多
The wildlings serve crueler Gods than you or I.
那些男婴 是卡斯特的祭品
Those boys are Craster's offerings.
祭品？
Offerings?
他谋杀亲子 简直就是禽兽
He's murdering his own children. He's a monster.
可是 很多时候 对我们的游骑兵来说
Aye, many a time that monster has been the difference
那禽兽手中攥着生与死的砝码
between life and death for our Rangers.
你叔叔肯定深有体会
Your Uncle among them.
我们还有别的仗要打
We have other wars to fight out there.
管你看不看得惯 我们都需要卡斯特这种人
Like it or not, we need men like Craster.
我……
I...
我看到那东西了
I saw it.
我看见
I saw...
有什么东西抱走了那婴儿
Something take that child.
好
Yeah.
不管那是啥
Whatever it was,
我敢说你还会再见到它
I daresay you'll see it again.
现在为我备马
Now ready my horse.
我们破晓动身
We leave at dawn.
别再把它弄丢了
Don't lose it again.
山姆威尔·塔利
守夜人事务官
吉莉
Gilly.
你要走了
You're leaving.
我——我一直想送你点什么
I-- I wanted to give you something.
这是我母亲留给我的
It belonged to my mother.
- 我不能收下  - 拜托了
- I can't take it.  - Please.
我希望你能拿着
I want you to.
我母亲从前用它做针线活
My mother used it for sewing.
缝衣服的时候 她都会叫我到她房间
She'd let me sit with her in her chamber while she sewed
坐在一旁念书给她听
and I'd read to her.
可父亲发现这事后 就明令禁止了
My father put a stop to it when he found out.
她的东西 我就只有这一件了
It's the only thing I have of hers.
在我离家来长城前 她送给了我
She gave it to me before I left for the Wall.
你——
You--
你不该把它送给不相关的人
you shouldn't give it away.
我不是送什么不相关的人
I'm not giving it away.
我送的是你
I'm giving it to you.
帮我好好保管它
Keep it safe for me.
等我回来
Till I come back.
“阿多”
马童
阿多
Hodor.
叫醒布兰 行么？他该上课了
Rouse Bran, will you? It's time for his lessons.
鲁温
临冬城学士
夏天
布兰的冰原狼
每晚都是如此
Every night it's the same.
布兰·史塔克
我在走
I'm walking
在跑，但是
and running, but...
我不是——我不是我
I'm not--I'm not me.
我穿梭于神木林
I'm running through the Godswood,
闻到尘土的味道
sniffing the dirt,
尝到口中鲜血的味道 我在捕猎杀戮
tasting blood in my mouth when I've made a fresh kill,
然后嚎叫
howling.
老奶妈给我讲过故事
Old Nan used to tell me stories
关于一些有魔力的人
about magical people who could live
他们能进入鹿、鸟、狼的体内
inside stags, birds, wolves.
准确来讲，布兰，那些只是——
That's exactly what they are, Bran--
- 故事罢了  - 那么她骗人了？
- stories.  - So she was lying?
- 他们不存在？  - 怎么说呢 他们或许曾经存在
- They don't exist?  - Well, they may have done.
但他们早就从这个世界消失了
But they're gone from the world
和其他古怪的事情一样
along with much else.
这些只是梦境 布兰
These are dreams, Bran,
仅此而已
nothing more.
不 我的梦是特别的
No, my dreams are different.
我梦到的都发生了
Mine are true.
我梦见过父亲的死亡
I dreamt of my father dying.
瑞肯也做过同样的梦
And Rickon had the same dream.
你做的梦不还有些是没有发生的么？
What about all the dreams you had that didn't come true?
嗯？
Hmm?
对了
Right.
这一环是由瓦雷利亚钢铸造的
This link is made of Valyrian steel.
一百个学士中只有一个能把它串进自己的锁链
Only one Maester in 100 wears it on his chain.
这代表我进修过所谓的“高级神秘术”
It signifies that I have studied the higher mysteries.
所有学习高级神秘术的人都忍不住想尝试施法
And all who study these mysteries try their hand at spells.
我也抵挡不住那诱惑
I was no different.
我当时还是个孩子
I was young.
哪个孩子不偷偷幻想在自己身上发现超常的力量
And what boy doesn't secretly wish for hidden powers
好让平凡的生活变得与众不同？
to lift him out of his dull life into a special one?
但最终 我费尽力气地尝试
But in the end, for all my efforts,
施法毫无效果 在我之前的1000个小子也是如此。
I got no more out of it than 1,000 boys before me.
来吧
Come on.
好了
All right.
或许魔法曾一度是这世界的主导力量
Maybe magic once was a mighty force in the world.
但已不再如此了
But not anymore.
巨龙消失了
The Dragons are gone.
巨人灭亡了
The Giants are dead.
森林之子也已被人遗忘
And the Children of the Forest forgotten.
蓝礼·拜拉席恩
高庭之王
玛格丽·提利尔
王后 梅斯·提利尔之女
洛拉斯！为高庭而战！
Loras! Highgarden!
- 拿下他！ - Get him!
哦！
Oh!
认输！我认输
Yield!I yield.
打得好 请上前
Well fought. Approach.
请起 摘下头盔
Rise. Remove your helm.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
洛拉斯·提利尔
“百花骑士”
你父亲对你并未夸大其词 女士
You are all your father promised and more, My Lady.
我只见洛拉斯爵士战败过一两次
I've seen Ser Loras bested once or twice,
但没有哪一次是这样狼狈的
but never quite in that fashion.
是呀 是呀 亲爱的陛下 我哥哥为您而战时 可是相当的勇猛啊
Now, now, my love. My brother fought valiantly for you.
他确实如此 我的王后
That he did, my Queen.
但冠军只有一个
But there can only be one champion.
塔斯的布蕾妮
Brienne of Tarth,
你可以向我索要任何一件东西
you may ask anything of me you desire.
只要是我能办到的 随便什么都可以
If it is within my power, it is yours.
陛下
Your Grace,
我恳请获得御林铁卫的荣誉职位
I ask the honor of a place in your Kingsguard.
- 什么？  - What?
我愿成为你七卫之一 为您献出我的生命
I will be one of your seven, pledge my life to yours,
并保护您免遭一切危难
and keep you safe from all harm.
同意
Done.
请起 御林铁卫 布蕾妮
Rise, Brienne of the Kingsguard.
陛下 我很荣幸地为您带来凯特琳·史塔克夫人
Your Grace, I have the honor to bring you Lady Catelyn Stark,
她是她儿子临冬城主罗柏·史塔克的使节
sent as an envoy by her son Robb, Lord of Winterfell.
是临冬城主以及北境之王
Lord of Winterfell and King in the North.
凯特琳·徒利
史塔克夫人
凯特琳夫人 很高兴见到你
Lady Catelyn. I'm pleased to see you.
请允许我向您介绍一下我的妻子 提利尔家族的玛格丽
May I present my wife Margaery of House Tyrell?
我们非常欢迎您 史塔克夫人
You are very welcome here, Lady Stark.
我对您的遭遇深表遗憾
I'm so sorry for your loss.
谢谢您的关心
You are most kind.
夫人
My Lady,
我向您起誓 我会让兰尼斯特
I swear to you I will see the Lannisters answer
为谋害您的丈夫而付出代价
for your husband's murder.
一旦我拿下君临
When I take King's Landing,
即刻把乔佛里的人头交给您
I'll bring you Joffrey's head.
听到您愿意伸张正义 我已心满意足了 大人
It will be enough to know that justice was done, My Lord.
陛下
Your Grace.
而且你应当在国王面前跪下说话
And you should kneel when you approach the King.
无需如此 史塔克夫人是我们的上宾
There's no need for that. Lady Stark is an honored guest.
您儿子是否已经向泰温·兰尼斯特进军了？
Has your son marched against Tywin Lannister yet?
我并不出席我儿子的作战会议
I do not sit on my son's war councils.
而就算我出席了 我也不会将他的计划透露给您
And if I did, I would not share his strategies with you.
如果罗柏史塔克要和我们谈条件 他最好是亲自前来
If Robb Stark wants a pact with us, he should come himself,
远胜过躲在妈妈的裙子后面
not hide behind his mother's skirts.
我儿子宁愿真刀真枪上阵杀敌
My son is fighting a war,
而非来这里比武作乐
not playing at one.
别担心 夫人
Don't worry, My Lady.
战争才刚刚开始
Our war is just beginning.
- 陛下 - 杰拉德
- Your Grace. - Gerard.
- 脚怎么样了？  - 好多了 陛下
- How's your foot?  - Better, Your Grace.
他们根本不知道自己该穿多大号的鞋子
They don't know their own size is all.
好小子
Good man.
我帐下有十万大军
I have 100,000 men at my command.
这是风暴地和河湾地的全部战力
All the might of the Stormlands and the Reach.
他们全都跟你的百花骑士一样年轻气盛吗？
And all of them young and bold like your Knight of Flowers?
这对你来说就像在玩一场游戏 对吗？
It's a game to you, isn't it?
- 我怜悯他们  - 为什么？
- I pity them.   - Why?
因为这情形维持不了多久
Because it won't last.
因为他们是夏天的骑士 而凛冬将至
Because they are the Knights of summer and winter is coming.
布蕾妮 护送凯特琳夫人回她的帐篷
Brienne, escort Lady Catelyn to her tent.
- 她旅途劳顿  - 是的 立刻 陛下
- She's tired from her journey.  - At once, Your Grace.
- 之后我还需要回来吗？   - 没必要
- Shall I return after?  - That won't be necessary.
我要祈祷一会儿 独自一个人
I would pray awhile.Alone.
请跟我来 夫人
If you'll follow me, My Lady.
您今天作战非常勇猛 布蕾妮小姐
You fought bravely today, Lady Brienne.
我为我的国王而战
I fought for my King.
不久以后我便会为他走上战场
Soon I'll fight for him on the battlefield.
如果需要的话 我会为他献出生命
Die for him if I must.
而且 如果您愿意的话 叫我布蕾妮就可以了
And, if it please you, Brienne's enough.
我不是什么千金小姐
I'm no lady.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
亚拉·葛雷乔伊
你在这儿做什么？
What are you doing here?
我住在这儿
I live here.
- 生我的气了 弟弟？  - 你这个说谎的婊子
- Are you angry with me, brother? - You lying bitch.
不是我的错  是你自己没认出我
It's not my fault you didn't recognize me.
认出你？  怎么可能？
Recognize you? How could I?
我最后一次见你……
The last time I saw you...
你看起来还是个胖小子
You looked like a fat little boy.
你那时也是个胖小子
You were a fat little boy, too,
但我还是认出你了
but I recognized you.
为什么不早告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
我打算先瞧瞧你现在是什么德行
I wanted to see who you were first.
还真是没让我失望
And I did.
我把一切都计划好了  你们只需留心听命便行
The plans are made. It's time you heard them.
- 父亲  - 父亲
- Father. - Father.
巴隆·葛雷乔伊
狼崽子已经向南方进军
The wolf pup has gone south
背后跟随着整个北方的兵力
with the entirety of the northern army at his back.
在他和西境与狮子纠缠时
While he's tangling with the lion in the Westerlands,
北境唾手可得
the north is ripe for the taking.
铁种将遵从古道
The Ironborn will reave and pillage as it was in the old days
在北境的西海岸展开掠夺
all along the northern coast.
之后将势力扩展到整片青绿之地
We'll spread our dominion across the green lands,
守住颈泽  以及整个北境
securing the Neck and everything above.
所有的城池都会一座接一座向我们投降
Every stronghold will yield to us one by one.
临冬城或许能坚守个一年半载  但那又怎样？
Winterfell may defy us for a year, but what of it?
剩下的地盘都是我们的了
The rest shall be ours--
森林 田野和厅堂
forest, field and hall.
雅拉我的女儿 你将率领三十条长船
Yara, my daughter, you'll take 30 longships
攻击深林堡
to attack Deepwood Motte.
我早想要座城堡啦
I've always wanted a castle.
那我的任务呢？
And what's my role in all this?
你带一条船 袭击磐石海岸 掠夺沿海渔村
You'll take a ship to raid the fishing villages on the Stoney Shore.
一条船？
A ship?
你给了她三十条 只给我一条？
You give her 30 and I get one?
海婊子号 我们认为她很适合你
The sea bitch. We thought she'd be perfect for you.
让我和渔民作战？
I'm to fight fishermen?
小心他们的渔网
Be careful of their nets.
父亲 我曾和罗柏·史塔克并肩作战 我了解他的部下
Father, I fought with Robb Stark. I know his men.
他不会轻易放弃北境的
He won't give up the North so easily.
在我们夺下北境之前  他们甚至都不会觉察
They won't even know we're there until it's too late.
你懂什么战争 女人？
What do you know of it, woman?
我是一个身经百战的战士
I'm a proven warrior.
你的两个哥哥也是战士 可惜他们都死了
Your brothers were warriors, both of them dead
死在那些你费尽心机想要袒护的人手里
at the hands of those you seem so eager to protect.
我没想袒护任何人
I'm not protecting anyone.
我只是在想  此时是否等待更为明智
I just wonder  if it's not wiser to wait.
北境完全有可能成为我们的盟友 为何要冒险与他们为敌？
Why risk going against the North if they would be our allies?
与他们开战 很可能会让我们全军覆没
Rise up against them and they could destroy us.
但是如果我们宣誓效忠
But if we pledge fealty to them,
他们会把凯岩城给我们
they'll give us Casterly Rock.
我们的家族箴言是什么？
What are our words?
家族箴言？
Our words?
- "强取胜于苦耕"   - "强取胜于苦耕"
- "We do not sow."  - "We do not sow."
我们是铁种
We are Ironborn.
不是臣民   不是奴隶
We're not subjects. We're not slaves.
不是田野里的耕牛  磨坊里的驴子
We do not plow the fields or toil in the mine.
我们夺取所有应该属于我们的东西
We take what is ours.
你和狼种在一起太久  变得懦弱了
Your time with the wolves has made you weak.
你说得好像我是自愿去和他们在一起的
You act as if I volunteered to go.
如果你记性够好  是你自己把我送给他们的
You gave me away, if you remember.
就在劳勃·拜拉席恩率军将你击溃之后
The day you bent the knee to Robert Baratheon.
你向他屈膝投降的那一天
After he crushed you.
那时你有没有努力保留属于你的东西？
Did you take what was yours then?
你亲手把我送给他们！
You gave me away!
你的亲儿子！
Your boy!
你唯一活着的亲儿子！
Your last boy!
你无情的送走了我   就像我是条你不想要的狗
You gave me away like I was some dog you didn't want anymore.
现在我回来了 你反而咒骂我
And now you curse me because I've come home.
你想让父亲向你的另一个小家族臣服？
You'd have our father bow down to your other family?
我没有另一个家族
I have no other family.
没有吗？
Don't you?
赶快做决定吧 席恩
Make your choice, Theon, and do it quickly.
有你没你 我们都一样出航
Our ships sail with or without you.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 代理首相
雪伊
你不会把我赶出这间屋子的
You won't let me leave this room.
- 你不会把我  - 嘘 嘘 小声点
- You won't let me--  - Shh, shh, keep your voice down.
为什么？你觉得你的父亲能听见我在说什么吗？
Why? You think your father can hear me?
他离我们有三百里远！
He's 300 miles away!
我不想让你留在这儿
I don't intend for you to stay here.
也许我可以让你混进城堡的厨房
I might be able to bring you into the castle kitchens.
当然 也只是暂时而已
Again, only temporary.
每一个尝过我厨艺的人都告诉我
Every man who has tasted my cooking
你真是个货真价实的妓女
has told me what a good whore I am.
不是让你去做厨娘
But you wouldn't be a cook.
是让你去做帮厨
You'd pose as a scullion.
帮厨？ 帮厨是什么？
Scullion? What is a scullion?
洗碗小妹
Kitchen wench.
- 洗碗小妹？  - 是的 不过--
- A kitchen wench?  - Yes, but--
洗盘子？
Cleaning pots?
我的小狮子想看我这个样子？
Is that how my lion wants to see me?
你的小狮子想让你活下去
Your lion wants to see you alive.
我们来到了一个危险的地方
We've come to a dangerous place.
我的姐姐看我不顺眼
My sister wants to hurt me.
她会努力寻找一切借口下手
She'll look for any weakness she can find.
她不能知道你的存在
She can't know about you.
我就是那个借口？
I'm the weakness?
这是个恭维呢 小姐
It's a compliment, My Lady.
成为借口怎么会是恭维？
How is being a weakness a compliment?
在这里 说话是需要艺术的
Language can be a bit tricky here.
噢 我太笨了 无法理解
Oh, I'm too stupid to understand.
笨笨的外国女孩
The stupid foreign girl.
我不做洗碗小妹
I am not a kitchen wench.
托曼·拜拉席恩
弥赛菈·拜拉席恩
珊莎·史塔克
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
摄政太后
乔佛里和珊莎什么时候结婚？
When will Joffrey and Sansa be married?
很快 亲爱的 等到战争结束
Soon, darling, when the war is over.
母亲说我将会得到一条新裙子参加婚礼
Mother says I'll have a new gown for the ceremony
宴会上还会有另外一条
and another for the feast.
但是你的新裙子将会是象牙色 因为你是新娘子
But yours will be ivory since you're the bride.
公主刚才在和你说话呢
The Princess just spoke to you.
对不起 陛下
Pardon, Your Grace.
我相信你的新裙子会很漂亮的 弥赛菈
I'm sure your dress will be beautiful, Myrcella.
我会数着日子 直到战争结束
I'm counting the days until the fighting is done
之后我会在七神面前献上我对国王的爱
and I can pledge my love to the King in sight of the Gods.
乔佛里会杀了珊莎的哥哥吗？
Is Joffrey going to kill Sansa's brother?
也许会
He might.
你希望如此吗？
Would you like that?
不 最好不要
No. I don't think so.
哪怕他这样做 珊莎还是会履行承诺的
Even if he does, Sansa will do her duty.
对吧 小小鸟？
Won't you, little dove?
请进
Come in.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是雪伊 小姐  您的新侍女
I'm Shae, My Lady. Your new handmaiden.
我并不知道我招了一名新侍女
I didn't know I needed a new handmaiden.
- 你不是本地人   - 不是
- You're not from here. - No.
你怎么还站着？
What are you doing?
等着您告诉我需要做什么
Waiting for you to tell me what to do.
我不需要告诉你该去做什么
I shouldn't have to tell you to do things.
你直接去做就好了
You should just do them.
做什么？
What things?
为我换床单 洗衣服
Change my linens, wash my clothing,
擦地 倒便壶 梳头
scrub the floor, empty my chamber pot, brush my hair.
- 不是这样   - 您说让我梳--
- No. - You said to brush--
不是现在
Not now.
您的便壶是空的
Your chamber pot is empty.
那就去擦桌子
Clean the table.
你以前做过侍女吗？
Have you ever been a handmaiden before?
- 是的   - 给谁做？
- Yes. - For whom?
- 朱瑞芙夫人   - 朱瑞芙夫人？
- Lady Zuriff. - Lady Zuriff?
朱瑞芙夫人
Lady Zuriff.
这城里没有叫朱瑞芙夫人的
There is no Lady Zuriff in this city.
她不在这座城里
She wasn't in this city.
好吧 我不知道侍女在那座城里怎样工作
Well, I don't know how they did things in that city,
但是在这里 侍女要把工作都提前做好
but in this city, handmaidens wait on ladies,
主人不会等待侍女
not the other way around.
而且我也没有时间回答一千零一问
And I don't have time to answer 1,000 questions
或者指导你该怎样工作
and teach you how to do your job.
您希望我退下吗？
Do you want me to leave?
给我梳梳头吧
Just brush my hair.
哦 感谢诸神
Oh, thank the Gods.
我已经六天没顺顺当当地大便了
I haven't had a proper shit in six days.
派席尔
首席学士
我以前也犯过便秘 大人
I've encountered this problem before, My Lord.
权力带来的压力容易引发这种
The stresses of power often have this
身体的不良症状
insalubrious effect.
每天用水服用两滴
Two drops with water daily.
好的 真高兴身边有您这样
Right. I'm so grateful to have a man
博学多闻的人
of your vast knowledge and wisdom on my side.
- 请坐   - 谢谢 大人
- Please. - Thank you, My Lord.
我能信任你 派席尔 是不是？
I can trust you, Pycelle, can I not?
啊 是的 当然 大人
Why, yes, of course, My Lord.
现在情况非常紧急
These are perilous times.
国王必须寻找新的盟友
And the crown must forge new alliances.
联姻无疑是最好的方式
And these alliances must often be sealed in matrimony.
联姻 嗯？
Matrimony, huh?
没错
Yes.
我相信御前会议会同意这项决定的
I'm trusting the council with these plans,
但是太后定不能知晓
but the queen mustn't know.
我们不能让她干涉
We can't have her meddling in affairs
这项将决定整个王国命运的计划
that could determine the future of the realm.
那样做风险太大
There's too much at stake.
噢 是的 是的 当然是
Oh, yes, yes. Indeed, yes.
我会守口如瓶的
I shall be silent as the grave.
我正在筹划跟多恩的马泰尔家族结盟
I'm brokering an alliance with House Martell of Dorne.
弥赛菈公主成年后会嫁给马泰尔家的幼子
Princess Myrcella will wed their youngest son
这样可以确保我们赢得他们的忠诚
when she comes of age,ensuring their loyalty
必要时还有他们的军队
and their army should we need it.
把弥赛菈送去多恩？
Myrcella sent away to Dorne?
但是要记住  太后定不能知晓
But remember, the queen mustn't know.
噢  太后定不能知晓
Ooh, "the queen mustn't know."
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”  情报总管
我喜欢这样的开场白
I love conversations that begin this way.
我打算把弥赛菈下嫁
I plan to marry Princess Myrcella off
给席恩·格雷乔伊
to Theon Greyjoy.
席恩·格雷乔伊？
Theon Greyjoy?
恕我直言  大人
Forgive me, My Lord?
他是临冬城的养子
He grew up a ward of Winterfell.
他追随罗柏·史塔克战斗
He fights for Robb Stark.
正是  但是席恩的父亲厌恶史塔克
Precisely. Theon's father loathes the Starks
他会说服他儿子站到我们这边
and will convince the boy to come to our side.
格雷乔伊可以从内部搞垮北方人
Greyjoy can destroy the northern army from within
他父亲的舰队也可以为我所用
and we can have his father's ships.
但是记住  谁也不能说
But remember, you must tell no one.
不能说什么？
Tell no one what?
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”  财政大臣
我打算把弥赛菈公主嫁给谷地的罗宾·艾林
I plan to wed Princess Myrcella to Robin Arryn of the Vale.
莱莎虽不喜欢我
Lysa is not fond of me.
但是也许皇家婚约
But perhaps the promise of a royal match
能够让她不计前嫌
will convince her to let bygones be bygones.
她把你投下了狱
She imprisoned you.
差点还结果了你
She tried to execute you.
你居然打算给她儿子配个公主？
And you offer her son a princess?
对于身处我们这样处境的人来说
For men in our position, holding grudges can be
记恨只会是累赘  不是吗？
an encumbrance, don't you think?
于是你打算让我去促成这门亲事咯？
And I suppose you want me to broker this agreement?
还能有谁呢？
Who better?
没错  只要我愿意
Yes, I could sing this song to Lysa,
我可以去跟莱莎说定这事
if I cared to.
但这对我有什么好处？
What's in it for me?
维斯特洛的民众会感激你
The gratitude of the people of Westeros
结束了这场战争
for helping to end this war,
国王也会感谢你夺回了谷地
the adoration of the King for bringing the Vale back into the fold...
还有赫伦堡
and Harrenhal.
赫伦堡是个不祥之地
Harrenhal is cursed.
不知道你也信这些东西
Never took you for a superstitious man.
随你自便  推倒再建个呗
By all means, tear it down and rebuild.
不用担心经费
You'll be able to afford it.
我还打算让你统领河间地呢
I plan to make you Lord of the Riverlands.
仅仅张张嘴  你就让我跻身于
With a single stroke, you'd make me one of the
王国最显赫的贵族之列？
greatest lords in the realm.
不仅这次  你一直在为我的家族尽心尽力
You served my family well in the matter of the succession.
杰诺斯·史林特也是一样  他同样受封赫伦堡
So did Janos Slynt, and he was given Harrenhal, too.
接着你又把城收了回去
Until you snatched it away.
我需要你联络莱莎·艾林
I need you to deliver Lysa Arryn.
我可不需要杰诺斯·史林特
I didn't need Janos Slynt.
那么就这么说定了？
It's settled, then?
很好
Good.
噢  对了
Oh, and remember--
太后定不能知晓
the queen mustn't know.
这样一定会很疼
That must hurt.
怎么？
What?
怎么了？
What is it?
她也配做御林铁卫？
A member of the Kingsguard?
好像我还没被羞辱够似的
As if I wasn't humiliated enough already.
布蕾妮武艺超群
Brienne is a very capable warrior.
忠心耿耿
And she's devoted to me.
你在吃醋
You're jealous.
吃醋？
Jealous?
吃“美人”布蕾妮的醋？
Of Brienne the beauty?
别开玩笑了
Don't make me laugh.
- 我来补偿你  - 不 陛下
- I'll make it up to you.  - No, Your Grace.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
今晚你该属于另外一个提利尔
There's another Tyrell who requires your attention.
仅凭个人魅力
You didn't win my father's support
你赢不到我父亲的支持和军队
or his army on charm alone.
你的封臣都在背后议论你
Your vassals are starting to snigger behind your back.
从没听说哪个新娘成婚半个月了还是处女的
Brides aren't usually virgins two weeks after their wedding night.
玛格丽是处女？
And Margaery's a virgin?
对外当然这么讲
Officially.
我带她过来？
Shall I bring her to you?
我先提醒你
I should warn you,
我喝得有点多
I've had quite a bit of wine.
你是国王  你做什么都没错
As is your right. You are a King.
你今晚很漂亮
You look very beautiful.
谢谢陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
- 衣服很好看  - 您喜欢？
- It's a lovely gown.  - You think so?
我不知道怎么穿更好
I can't decide how I like it better.
这样
This way...
还是这样
or this way.
你没必要这么做
You certainly don't need it.
虽然……
Although...
人们说含蓄的美
some say that beauty most desired
才最是撩拨心弦
is the beauty concealed.
该是那酒
Must be the wine.
来 让我来
Here, let me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
要让我哥哥进来帮忙吗？
Do you want my brother to come in and help?
- 什么？  - 他能让你硬起来
- What?  - He could get you started.
我知道他不会介意的
I know he wouldn't mind.
要不然我转过身去你假装在跟他做
Or I can turn over and you can pretend I'm him.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你没必要跟我绕弯子
There's no need for us to play games.
把掩饰都留在宫廷上吧  别在这里就用光了
Save your lies for court. You're going to need a lot of them.
你的敌人不喜欢我们的联姻
Your enemies aren't happy about us.
他们想要拆散我们
They want to tear us apart.
要阻止他们
And the best way to stop them
最好是让我
is to put your baby
给你生个孩子
in my belly.
我们可以慢慢来
We can try again later.
跟我做也好  加上洛拉斯一起来也好
You decide how you want to do it--
你想怎么做都行
with me, with me and Loras.
你想怎样都行
However else you like.
你要做什么都可以
Whatever you need to do.
你是国王
You are a King.
你这混蛋
You monster.
我就弥赛菈这一个女儿
Myrcella is my only daughter.
你居然认为我会任你把她当妓女卖了？
Do you really think I'll let you sell her like a common whore?
弥赛菈是王国的公主
Myrcella's a Princess.
从某种意义上讲  这是她与生俱来的使命
Some would say she was born for this.
我绝不同意你把弥赛菈装船卖给多恩人
I will not let you ship her off to Dorne
就像我当年被卖给劳勃·拜拉席恩一样！
as I was shipped off to Robert Baratheon.
在多恩她会很安全
Dorne is the safest place or her.
你疯了吗？马泰尔家族恨我们入骨
Are you mad? The Martells loathe us.
所以我们才要拉拢他们
That's why we need to seduce them.
为了你儿子掀起的这场战争
We're going to need their support in the war
我们需要他们的支持
your son started.
- 她是去做人质  - 她是多恩的贵宾
- She'll be a hostage.  - A guest.
我不会善罢甘休的
You won't get away with this.
你以为父亲给你的那张纸就能当挡箭牌了？
You think the piece of paper father gave you keeps you safe.
奈德·史塔克也有一张
Ned Stark had a piece of paper, too.
- 决定了 瑟曦  - 不
- It's done, Cersei.  - No.
- 不可能回头  - 不！
- You cannot stop it.  - No!
倘若君临城破弥赛菈又岂会安全？
Just how safe do you think Myrcella is if this city falls?
你想要她跟坦格里安家族的孩子一样被强暴  屠杀吗？
Do you want to see her raped, butchered like the Targaryen children?
为防万一
Make no mistake.
他们会把弥赛菈的漂亮脑袋插在你旁边
They'll mount her pretty little head on a spike right beside yours.
滚！滚！
Get out! Get out!
罗柏
我希望你看到此信时还不算太晚,我父亲他拒绝了你的提议
并且密谋偷袭北境，铁舰队将劫掠沿海并进军深林堡
你要尽快召集人手做好防备，否则一切就将太迟了
一旦有机会，我会继续和你联系！
罗柏
我希望你看到此信时还不算太晚,我父亲他拒绝了你的提议
并且密谋偷袭北境，铁舰队将劫掠沿海并进军深林堡
你要尽快召集人手做好防备，否则一切就将太迟了
一旦有机会，我会继续和你联系！
格雷乔伊家族的席恩
Theon of the House Greyjoy,
你愿意把自己献给淹神吗？
you would this day consecrate your faith to the drowned God?
- 我愿意  - 跪下
- I would.  - Kneel.
让您的仆人席恩
Let Theon, your servant,
如您一般自海中重生！
be born again from the sea as you were.
给予他海盐的祝福
Bless him with salt.
给予他坚石的祝福
Bless him with stone.
给予他钢铁的祝福
Bless him with steel.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
What is dead may never die...
必将再起  其势更烈
But rises again harder and stronger.
起来
Stand.
侏儒  我不喜欢被人忽悠
I don't appreciate being made a fool of, dwarf.
弥赛菈既然要嫁给马泰尔家的儿子
If Myrcella marries the Martell boy,
她还怎么嫁给罗宾·艾林？
she can't very well marry Robin Arryn, can she?
是啊  恐怕嫁不成了  很抱歉
No, afraid not. Sorry about that.
那么赫伦堡——
And Harrenhal--
恐怕也不在协定之内了
I suppose that's off the table as well.
是啊 恐怕不行了 这件事也很抱歉
Yes, I fear so. Sorry about that, too.
再有骗人的戏码别再搭上我了
Leave me out of your next deception.
噢  太遗憾了
Oh, that's a shame.
我本来打算让你在下一场里唱头角儿呢
You were to be the centerpiece of my next deception.
我哥哥詹姆还在北方人手里
My brother Jaime rots in a Northern stockade.
我希望他们能放了他
I would see him released.
这件事非你不可
That's where you come in.
罗柏·史塔克不可能放了弑君者
Robb Stark will never release the Kingslayer.
他当然不会  但他母亲也许可以
No, he won't. But his mother might.
你很想再次见到你亲爱的凯特吧？
How would you like to see your beloved Cat again?
- 找到了？  - 噢 是的
- Find him?  - Oh, aye.
他还有个伴
And he has company.
实在不忍心打断这恶心的老鼬鼠
Filthy old stoat. Almost hate to interrupt.
- 不  你不用  - 我没打断他
- No, you don't.  - No, I don't.
波隆
都城守备队长
夏嘎
这是干什么？
What is the meaning of this?
轻点  轻点
No, please, please.
大学士  你让我很失望
You disappoint me, Grand Maester.
我是您忠诚的仆人
I am your loyal servant.
你把我要送弥赛菈去多恩的计划告诉太后
So loyal that you told the Queen about my plans
真是太忠诚了
to send Myrcella to Dorne.
不！不对！
No! Never!
这不是实情 我发誓
It's a falsehood. I swear it.
不是我走漏的消息
It wasn't me.
啊  瓦里斯
Ah, Varys.
是八爪蜘蛛瓦里斯干的
It was Varys the spider.
听着  我告诉瓦里斯要把弥赛菈送给格雷乔伊家
See, I told Varys that I was giving the Princess to the Greyjoys.
我对小指头说的则是把弥赛菈嫁给罗宾·艾林
I told Little finger that I planned to wed her to Robin Arryn.
至于将弥赛菈送去多恩的打算
I told no one that I was offering her to the Dornish.
除了你我从没给任何人提过
No one but you.
到处都是太监的小小鸟儿
The eunuch has spies everywhere.
把他的命根子剁了喂山羊
Cut off his manhood and feed it to the goats.
- 不不不  - 半人  这里没有山羊
- No, no, no.  - There are no goats, halfman.
砍了再说
Well, make do.
你替我姐姐当眼线有多久了？
How long have you been spying for my sister?
我所做的一切 全是为了兰尼斯特家族
All I did, I did for House Lannister.
向来都……去问您的父亲大人  去问问他
Always. Your lord father, ask him.
从疯王当政的年代起
I've always been his servant
我就一直都是他忠诚的仆人
since the days of the Mad King.
- 我不喜欢他的胡子 - 什么？
- I don't like his beard. - What?
什么？ 噢  不  不！
What? Oh, no. No.
派席尔 你到底出卖过多少首相？
How many hands have you betrayed, Pycelle?
艾德·史塔克？ 琼恩·艾林？
Eddard Stark? Jon Arryn?
艾林大人 他知道……
Lord Arryn, he knew.
他知道关于太后的真相
He knew the truth about the queen.
而且  他想采取行动
And, well, he planned to act,
告诉劳勃国王
to tell King Robert.
所以你抢先毒死了他
So you poisoned him?
不 没有！
No. Never.
但你放任他死去 确保他一命呜呼
But you let him die, made sure he succumbed.
兰尼斯特 我做的一切都是为了兰尼斯特
Lannister-- I always served Lannister.
把他带走 扔进黑牢
Get him out of my sight. Throw him in one of the black cells.
不  不  不要！不 求求您
Oh, no. No, no, no. No, please.
不！你不能这样对我！
Don't! You can't do this to me!
打扰你了
For your trouble.
我们共同的好朋友服侍珊莎小姐的不错
You'll be pleased to know our mutual friend
您想必乐见这好消息
is doing quite well in Lady Sansa's service.
很好  算我出了一个好主意
Good.One of my better ideas.
看起来大学士派席尔
And it seems the Grand Maester
似乎找到了一条去黑牢的路
has found his way into a black cell.
玩的漂亮 首相大人
Well played, My Lord Hand.
但我是不是该担心一下？
But should I be worried?
杰诺斯·史林特  派席尔
Janos Slynt, Pycelle--
本就不多人的御前会议每天都在减少
the small council grows smaller every day.
御前会议在对待过去的首相上名声不好
The council has a reputation for serving past Hands poorly.
我可不想追随奈德·史塔克进坟墓
I don't mean to follow Ned Stark to the grave.
大人 权力是个有趣的玩意儿
Power is a curious thing, My Lord.
您喜欢谜语吗？
Are you fond of riddles?
怎么 你想说一个给我听听？
Why, am I about to hear one?
三位地位显赫之人坐在一个房间
Three great men sit in a room.
一位国王 一位僧侣 和一位富翁
A king, a priest and a rich man.
有个出身寒微的佣兵站在他们中间
Between them stands a common Sellsword.
每位显赫之人都命令他杀死另外两人
Each great man bids the sellsword kill the other two.
孰生？孰死？
Who lives, who dies?
这得看那个佣兵了
Depends on the Sellsword.
是吗？他既无王冠
Does it? He has neither crown
也无财宝 更无神佑
nor gold nor favor with the Gods.
他有把剑呐 权掌生死
He has a sword,the power of life and death.
既然真正决定我们生死的是手握刀剑之人
But if it's swordsmen who rule,
我们又为何假装承认国王握有力量？
why do we pretend Kings hold all the power?
当奈德·史塔克被砍头时
When Ned Stark lost his head,
谁是真正的责任人？
who was truly responsible?
乔佛里？刽子手？
Joffrey? The executioner?
还是……另有其人？
Or something else?
我现在认为我不喜欢谜语了
I've decided I don't like riddles.
权力的力量寄寓于人心所在
Power resides where men believe it resides.
它是个把戏
It's a trick,
如浮墙魅影
a shadow on the wall.
即便是身材矮小之人
And a very small man
也能投下遮天巨影
can cast a very large shadow.
"阿利"
艾莉亚·史塔克
尤伦
“浪鸦”  守夜人
你该睡了
You should be sleeping.
明天路程很长
Tomorrow's a long march.
天不撒尿那也有三十里
30 miles if it don't piss on us.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
我不喜欢那味道
I don't like the taste.
呃……
Well...
说实在的  喝东西又不是为了味道
You don't drink it for the flavor, to be honest.
什么？
What?
你怎么睡觉？
How do you sleep?
和大多数人一样吧  我想
Same as most men,I think.
但你会看到那些东西
But you've seen things,
可怕的东西
horrible things.
是
Aye.
但我也会看到漂亮的东西
I've seen some pretty things, too,
虽然它们不太多
but not nearly so many.
你怎么能睡得安稳 当——
How do you sleep when you--
当你脑袋里那些东西浮现在眼前
when you have those things in your head?
你装作没看见
You didn't see that.
我他妈保证
I made damn sure.
我只要闭上眼 就能看到他们站在那里
I close my eyes and I see them up there.
所有人
All of them
站在那儿
standing there--
乔佛里
Joffrey,
太后
the Queen,
还有
and--
我的姐姐
and my sister.
知道么  我们之间其实有些类似  你与我
You know, we've got something in common, me and you.
你知道吗？
You know that?
我那时候
I must have been
比你大几岁
a couple of years older than you.
我站在我家门阶上
I saw my brother stabbed through the heart
看着我哥被一把匕首刺穿心脏
right on our doorstep.
那个把他刺成串儿的不是什么恶棍
He weren't much of a villain what skewered him.
那小子  他叫威廉
Willem, the lad's name was.
吐一口痰的功夫都不到  他就跑的没影儿
He ran off before anyone could spit.
而我只是站在那里
And I just stood there,
眼睁睁看着我哥死去
watching my brother die.
但好笑的是
But here's the funny part.
我再也想不起我哥的脸
I can't picture my brother's face anymore.
但是威廉
But Willem--
噢 他长得还挺俊俏
oh, he was a nice-looking boy.
一口大白牙
He had good white teeth,
蓝眼睛
blue eyes,
有那种女孩们都喜欢的小酒窝
one of those dimpled chins all the girls like.
我干活的时候 喝酒的时候
I would think about him when I was working
拉屎的时候 都在想他
when I was drinking, when I was having a shit.
后来一发不可收拾
It got to the point
每晚上床睡觉之前 我都要默念他的名字
where I would say his name every night before I went to bed.
威廉  威廉
Willem. Willem.
威廉
Willem.
就像祈祷
A prayer almost.
直到有一天……
Well, one day...
威廉骑着马回到小镇
Willem came riding back into town.
我一斧子奋力砸进了他脑壳里
I buried an ax so deep into Willem's skull,
以至于他们都没拔出来就把他葬了
they had to bury him with it.
威廉的马把我带到长城
Willem's horse got me to the Wall
从那以后我就成了守夜人
and I've been wearing black ever since.
行了
Well...
这能帮你好好睡觉吗 啊？
that'll help you sleep, eh?
喂！
Ho!
懒鬼和婊子们 都起来！
Get up, you lazy sons of whores!
詹德利
“大牛”
罗米
“绿手”
“热派”
带上武器
Arm yourselves.
- 起来  - 起来
- Get up.  - Get up.
你们俩个都给我藏着点
Keep out of sight,both of you.
- 我不害怕  - 我能战斗
- No, I'm not afraid.  - I can fight.
记住藏好了
Keep out of sight.
如果出了什么差错  就逃
If things go wrong, you run.
听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
径直往北 再也别回头
You run along North and don't look back.
嘿！外面有人
Hey, there's men out there
妄想操你们的尸体
who want to fuck your corpses.
全都出去 马上！
Outside, now!
快 动起来 快！
Come on, move, move!
是金袍子！
Gold Cloaks!
所有人都出去！
Everyone out!
喂 你！把这该死的笼子打开！
Hey, you! Open the damn cage!
乌鸦  那杂种在哪儿？
Where's the bastard, Crow?
我这儿有的是杂种  谁在问话？
Got more than a few bastards here. Who's asking?
我乃亚摩利·洛奇爵士 泰温·兰尼斯特大人的封臣
Ser Amory Lorch, sworn Bannerman to Lord Tywin Lannister.
这些从都城来的人需要我们的协助
These men from the capitalrequested our assistance.
以国王名义放下武器
Drop your weapons in the name of the King.
这会儿你说的是哪个国王？
Now, which King would that be?
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
以乔佛里国王之名
In the name of King Joffrey,
亚摩利·洛奇
泰温麾下骑士
放下武器
drop your weapons.
我觉得不行
I don't think I will.
那好吧
So be it.
所以我向来讨厌十字弓  装填太麻烦了
I always hated crossbows. Take too long to load.
小子 到这儿来 小子！
Jaqen: Boy, come here.Boy!
- 好小子 帮帮我们  - 回这儿来！
- Sweet boy, help us.  - Come back here!
小子  帮帮我们！
Help us, boy!
某人可以战斗！ 放了我们！
A man can fight! Free us!
快点 把它给我
Quick, give it to me.
把斧子给我  把它给我
Give me the ax.Give me that.
贾昆·赫加尔
把他们放在马车上！
Put 'em on the wagon!
这儿还有 过来
There's more here.Come on.
看看这儿又是啥啊？
What do we have here?
不要！
No!
是把漂亮的小刀片儿
That's a fine little blade.
或许我会用它来剔牙
Maybe I'll pick my teeth with it.
我投降！我投降！
I yield! I yield!
把活着的都聚起来
Amory: Round up any survivors.
我们要带他们回赫伦堡
We'll take them back to Harrenhal.
你听到他说的了 跟我们走
You heard him. You're coming with us.
我投降！
I yield!
救命！
Help!
救救我！
Help me!
小子 你的腿怎么了？
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
你看看它
Look at it.
能走路吗？
Can you walk?
不 你得背我
No.You got to carry me.
好吧
All right.
他叫我背他嘞
Carry him, he says.
我们在找一个叫詹德利的杂种
We're looking for a bastard named Gendry.
供出来
Give him up
不然我就开始挨个挖眼珠子
or I'll start taking eyeballs.
你要詹德利
You want Gendry?
你已经抓到他了
You already got him.
他一直很爱那头盔
He loved that helmet.
衣柜字幕组出品